Okay, so in this lesson that we're going to look at how to use Visual Studio Code with TypeScript,
we offer a node that Visual Studio Code is perhaps one of the best editors for TypeScript
because it gives us intelligence, type checking, debugging, and a great developer experience.
Now, we've had a look in the previous lesson how to do the TypeScript compiler, TSC,
in a simple and notepad file. Obviously, we don't want to do it in notepad because we've got a
Visual Studio Code. Now, the tools you're going to need to first of all make sure you have node installed,
so make sure you go to terminal prompts, first of all, and to node, and then V for version.
If you haven't got node installed, then you just do a quick Google search and get that installed
on your system. You also want to make sure you have MPM installed as well. Again, just do MPM
hyphen V and should output the version of MPM, and once again, just pop up to the internet,
friendly Google, and grabs your copy of MPM. Now, you can obviously need to install TypeScript,
and we learned how to do that in the previous lesson, so you should already have that on your
machine by now. Let's do TSC version, and she had the version of TypeScript. If you don't have
it installed, you can do MPM, install, hyphen G, and then TypeScript, and that's pretty much it.
You should have everything you need to be able to do some TypeScript development.
So, I'm just going to go to a folder, let's just create yourselves, open a folder,
let's just go to our TypeScript folder here. Okay, it's going to blank folder to work with.
Going to create a new file, just like we did in the previous example, but we're now
going to get inside Visual Studio Code, so let's do hello.ts. We're going to use the same code as we did
in the previous example, so let's message. Notice, as we type in Visual Studio Code,
we of course get IntelliSense support, so if we type S, we get the option to do it as a string,
so we can then define it, the hello VS Code, TypeScript, and let's just output our message,
so console, and then we call this HubLog, and then it puts our message. Okay, so that's our
hello.ts file, and of course, we can now go to a terminal prompt, and we can compile this guy,
and convert it into JavaScript, so we can do TSC, and then do hello.ts.
Just like it did in the previous lesson, which now created ourselves a JavaScript file,
and let's remove the types just like I did before. Now we can do this, we can execute that,
we can go to a terminal prompt and do node, and then hello.js, and then we get our outputs by
hello VS Code, TypeScript, so you can see how easy it is to actually create some TypeScript
in Visual Studio Code. Now when our project grows, compiling individual files comes rather
inefficient, so instead we can create ourselves a TS config JSON file that's basically
tells TypeScript how to compile our entire project, and we can do that again inside our terminal
prompt by doing TSC, hyphen, hyphen, and then in it, and IT. Execute that, and it creates us a
TS config JSON file with a whole load of defaults here. And then what we can do is that allows us
to compile everything inside our folder just by doing TSC without specifying the name of the file,
and it's going to output and create our whole compile or whole load of stuff, including
these mapping files, allowing us to be able to do things like debugging and stuff like that.
So we get more options because of this config file than just calling the command directly,
and this is going to be great for our development because we never have to rerun the
compiler for each file manually. In the next session, we're going to expand upon this
by installing some extensions, also learning how to do some debugging in TypeScript in Visual Studio
code.